<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-09-11T22:52:31-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">David Galstyan’s CIT 480 Blog</title><subtitle>Welcome!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Blog 1: An Update for the QR App (somewhat)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/11/Blog1-QR-Scanner-Update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blog 1: An Update for the QR App (somewhat)" /><published>2020-09-11T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-09-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/11/Blog1-QR-Scanner-Update</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/11/Blog1-QR-Scanner-Update.html">&lt;p&gt;(&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: See my &lt;a href=&quot;https://davidgalstyan53.github.io/2020/09/04/Blog0-QR-Scanner-Application.html&quot;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; for background)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The layout of the QR code application has been drawn out, and our first sprint is underway. The sprint will be due to finish on the 23rd of September, so this will give me plenty of time to implement and debug some of the PHP files. This is a rough draft of what the site (not the application) will cover:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;!(https://davidgalstyan53.github.io/QR_PHP.png)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I stated in the previous blog entry, I will be using my COMP484 final project as a reference guide for the user login system. You will find the repo at my GitHub page &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/davidgalstyan53&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">(NOTE: See my previous post for background)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Blog 0: QR Scanner Application</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/04/Blog0-QR-Scanner-Application.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blog 0: QR Scanner Application" /><published>2020-09-04T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-09-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/09/04/Blog0-QR-Scanner-Application</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/09/04/Blog0-QR-Scanner-Application.html">&lt;p&gt;I must admit, I found myself to be a bit short for words here. For the past couple of weeks I haven’t spent much time looking into some of the things that I had been planning to look into to prepare me for CIT480. Those things would have included:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Terraform&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ansible&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Playing around with my newly acquired AWS Education credits&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Building on my knowledge of Docker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, most of my time has gone towards planning out my group’s project for CIT496P. Since Professor Kaplan has decided to revamp the course into a DevOps practicum, we’ve actually seen a massive influx of CompSci students (eww) take the course to fill in the “Dev” roles on each team. Despite being a CIT major, I’ve actually taken in interest taking one of the “Dev” roles in the team, mainly due to my working (and still improving) knowledge of full stack development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-will-the-application-do&quot;&gt;What will the application do?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The application is a QR Attendance system meant to be used by CSUN students to log into their respective courses. Students will be required to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Log into their CSUN accounts on their phones (using our mobile app)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Log on to the attendance site (also built by us), and choose the course they are attending&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If the student wishes to check in, they will be prompted with a QR code, which they will scan with their phone application&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If the student can not attend class, there will be an option for the student to request an absence excuse&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instructors will also be able to log in to the site to view their course attendance records, course rosters, and attendance excuse submissions from students.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-do-we-plan-to-achieve-this&quot;&gt;How do we plan to achieve this?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The attendance site will be built and hosted on a LAMP stack on an AWS server. The database schema is currently being constructed by other team members. As of right now, the plan is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build the mobile application with Java using Android Studio&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The backend of the entire web and mobile applications will be built with PHP and a MySQL database&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The PHP user login and session tracking will largely re-use code that used I built my final COMP484 project (a user login and registration system) with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-are-some-issues-that-we-will-run-into&quot;&gt;What are some issues that we will run into?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where do I start?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Students can easily share their login information to falsely check into a class&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The database schema will likely take some time to draw out and Build&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;While Android Studio provides an extremely beginner-friendly platform, it will take some time to transition to building mobile applications&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Even if the Android application deployment is a success, we would also have to go about building the application for iOS as well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;overall&quot;&gt;Overall?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some fixes that we have in mind for the issues above, but these are still pending, as the project is still in it’s early stages. I’m planning to write another blog post about this project once we are finished with our first sprint. Until then, I’m hoping to look into writing about automation tools if I get the chance this upcoming week.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I must admit, I found myself to be a bit short for words here. For the past couple of weeks I haven’t spent much time looking into some of the things that I had been planning to look into to prepare me for CIT480. Those things would have included:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/09/01/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2020-09-01T14:18:49-07:00</published><updated>2020-09-01T14:18:49-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/09/01/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2020/09/01/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll requires blog post files to be named according to the following format:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YEAR-MONTH-DAY-title.MARKUP&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YEAR&lt;/code&gt; is a four-digit number, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MONTH&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DAY&lt;/code&gt; are both two-digit numbers, and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MARKUP&lt;/code&gt; is the file extension representing the format used in the file. After that, include the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</summary></entry></feed>